<tei xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc xml:id="_1" />
        <encodingDesc/>
    </teiHeader>
    <text xml:lang="en">
		<p>Superconductivity and Quantum Criticality in <material>CeCoIn 5</material></p>
		<p><me_method>Electrical resistivity measurements</me_method> on a single crystal of the <class>heavy-fermion</class> superconductor <material>CeCoIn5</material> at pressures to <pressure>4.2 GPa</pressure> reveal a strong crossover in transport properties near P * ≈ <pressure>1.6 GPa</pressure>, where <tc>Tc</tc> is a maximum. The temperature-pressure phase diagram constructed from these data provides a natural connection to <class>cuprate</class> physics, including the possible existence of a pseudogap.</p>
		<p>PACS numbers: 74.70.Tx, 74.62.Fj, 75.30.Mb, 75.40.-s</p>
		<p>The relationship between unconventional superconductivity and quantum criticality is emerging as an important issue in strongly correlated materials, including <class>cuprates</class>, organics and heavy-fermion intermetallics . In each of these, either Nature or an externally imposed parameter, such as pressure or chemical substitutions, tunes some magnetic order to a T = 0 transition where quantum fluctuations introduce new excitations that control thermodynamic and transport properties over a broad range of temperature-parameter phase space. A frequent, but controversial , assumption is that these same excitations may mediate Cooper pairing in the anisotropic superconductivity that appears in the vicinity of a quantum-critical point (QCP). Indeed, the effective potential generated by proximity to a quantum-critical spin-density wave also can lead to anisotropic superconductivity.</p>
		<p>Though the issue of quantum criticality and superconductivity came to prominence in the context of the <class>cuprates</class> (see, eg ), there have been several recent examples of this interplay in <class>heavy-fermion compounds</class> . Like the <class>cuprates</class>, <tc>unconventional superconductivity</tc> in these <class>Ce-based heavy-fermion materials</class> develops out of a distinctly non-Fermi-liquid normal state that evolves in proximity to a continuous T = 0 antiferromagnetic transition; but unlike the <class>cuprates</class>, this state can be accessed cleanly by applied hydrostatic pressure and without introducing extrinsic disorder associated with chemical substitutions. In addition to chemical inhomogeneity in the <class>cuprates</class>, a further &#x27;complication&#x27; is the existence of a pseudogap state above <tc>T c</tc> for dopings less than optimal . Whether evolution of the pseudogap with doping produces another QCP near the optimal <tc>T c</tc> in the <class>cuprates</class> is an open question as is the origin of the pseudogap . Thus far, a pseudogap has not been detected in <class>canonical quantum-critical heavy-fermion systems</class>, such as <material id="12">CeIn 3</material> or <material id="13">CePd 2 Si 2</material> under pressure, but this may not be too surprising. In these cases, <tc>superconductivity</tc> appears only at very low temperatures, <tcValue id="14" ptr="#12,#13">less than 0.4 K</tcValue>, and over a narrow window of pressures (<pressure ptr="#14">≤ 0.8 GPa</pressure>) centered around the pressure where T N extrapolates to zero. In analogy to the <class>cuprates</class>, we would expect a pseudogap in these Ce compounds to exist only over a narrow temperature window, 0.1 − 0.2 K above <tc>T c</tc>, and in a fraction of the narrow pressure window, which certainly would make detection of a pseudogap difficult.</p>
		<p><material>CeCoIn 5</material> offers the possibility of making a connection between other <class>Ce-based heavy-fermion materials</class> and the <class>cuprates</class>. <tc>Bulk, unconventional superconductivity</tc> is present in <material>CeCoIn 5</material> at <pressure>atmospheric pressure</pressure> and develops out of a heavy-fermion normal state in which the <me_method>resistivity</me_method> is approximately linear in temperature. Application of a magnetic field sufficient to <tc>quench superconductivity</tc> reveals a <me_method>specific heat</me_method> diverging as −T ln T and associated low-temperature entropy consistent with its huge zero-field <me_method>specific heat</me_method> jump at T c (∆C/γT c = 4.5). Together, these properties suggest that <material>CeCoIn 5</material> may be near an antiferromagnetic quantum-critical point at P = 0. Its isostructural, antiferromagnetic relative <material id="26">CeRhIn 5</material> becomes a pressureinduced unconventional superconductor near <pressure ptr="#29">1.6 GPa</pressure>, with a <tc>T c</tc> = <tcValue id="29" ptr="#26">2.1 K</tcValue> close to that of <material>CeCoIn 5</material> at P = <pressure>0</pressure> . This and other similarities between <material>CeCoIn 5</material> at P = <pressure>0</pressure> and <material>CeRhIn 5</material> at P = <pressure>1.6 GPa</pressure> reinforce speculation that the nearby antiferromagnetic QCP in <material>CeCoIn 5</material> may be at an inaccessible slightly negative pressure. The 1.7% smaller cell volume of <material>CeCoIn 5</material> compared to that of <material>CeRhIn 5</material> is consistent with this view. We have studied the effect of pressure on the <me_method>electrical resistivity</me_method> and superconductivity of <material>CeCoIn 5</material> and find striking correlations between them that are reminiscent of <class>cuprate</class> behaviors.</p>
		<p>Four-probe AC <me_method>resistivity</me_method> measurements, with current flowing in the tetragonal basal plane, were made on a single crystal of <material>CeCoIn 5</material> grown from excess In flux. Hydrostatic pressures to 5 GPa were generated in a toroidal anvil cell in which a boron-epoxy gasket surrounds a teflon capsule filled with a glycerol-water mixture (3:2 volume ratio) that served as the pressure transmitting fluid. Pressure inside the capsule was determined at room temperature and at low temperatures from the pressuredependent <me_method>electrical resistivity</me_method> and <tc>T c</tc> of Pb, respectively . The width of <tc>superconducting transition</tc> of Pb did not exceed 15 mK, indicating good hydrostatic conditions and providing an estimate of the pressure-measurement uncertainty, ±0.04 GPa.</p>
		<p>The response of ρ(T ) to pressure over a broad temperature scale is typical of many Ce-based heavy-</p>
		<p>Effect of pressure on the low-temperature <me_method>resistivity</me_method> and <tc>superconducting Tc</tc> of <material>CeCoIn5</material>. The inset shows the <me_method>resistivity</me_method> ρ normalized by ρ(T + c ) up to 10 K. fermion compounds and reflects a systematic increase in the energy scale of spin fluctuations. Most interesting is the low-temperature response (where <tc>T c</tc> and the <me_method>resistivity</me_method> just above <tc>T c</tc> (ρ(T + c ) decrease rapidly with pressures P &gt; 1.35 GPa. We have analyzed the low temperature <me_method>resistivity</me_method>, plotted over a broader temperature scale in the inset of , by either fitting to a form ρ(T ) = ρ 0 + AT n , with ρ 0 , A and n fitting parameters, or from plots of (ρ(T ) − ρ 0 )/T n . A drawback to the former approach is that parameters can be sensitive to the temperature range chosen for fitting. The more sensitive and revealing approach is the latter in which ρ 0 and n are adjusted to give the best horizontal line. This procedure requires one less parameter, A, which is provided directly by the magnitude of (ρ(T ) − ρ 0 )/T n . Representative examples of this approach are plotted in . Parameters obtained from these plots are well defined and agree, typically to 10% or better, with parameter values extracted from straightforward fits. As indicated by arrows on the lowest pressure curve in , (ρ(T ) − ρ 0 )/T n deviates from the horizontal trend at a temperature T pg well above the <tc>onset of superconductivity</tc>. This departure implies either a decrease in the scattering rate or increase in carrier density. Resistivity measurements at P = 0 and in a magnetic field (6 T) greater than H c2 (0) find a similar departure of (ρ(T ) − ρ 0 )/T n from a T -independent curve at T pg =3 K. Thus, T pg does not originate from superconducting fluctuations or from trace amounts of free indium. We also note that this behavior was present in previous measurements on other <material>single crystals CeCoIn 5</material> but was missed in inspections of ρ versus T curves . We will return to a discussion of T pg later.</p>
		<p>Values of ρ 0 , n and A obtained from these plots are summarized in</p>
		<p>and b. There is an unmistakable crossover in the pressure dependence of ρ 0 and Representative plots of (ρ(T ) − ρ0)/T n vs T . At low pressures, (ρ(T ) − ρ0)/T n is constant from Tpg ≈ (1.15 ± 0.05)Tc to about 10 K. At the higher pressures, there is a well-defined range below TF The resistive <tc>onset of superconductivity</tc>, defined by the intersection of linear extrapolations of ρ(T ) from above and below <tc>Tc</tc>, is denoted by dashed vertical arrows. At the highest pressures, the gradual rounding just above <tc>Tc</tc> is due to a broadened transition (see ) and not to Tpg n at P * ≈ 1.6 GPa. Below P * , n = 1.0 ± 0.1 for T pg ≤ T ≤ 10 K. This value of n is expected for a 2dimensional, antiferromagnetic quantum-critical system and is not too surprising given the layered crystal structure and anisotropy in electronic states of CeCoIn 5 . At pressures greater than P * , n rapidly approaches the Fermi-liquid value of 2.0, which holds from just above <tc>T c</tc> to T F L (see ). Though not shown in either or 3a, at these higher pressures n assumes a value of 1.5±0.1, characteristic of a 3-D antiferromagnetic QCP, in a temperature interval from slightly greater than T F L to as high as ∼ 60 K. For P ≥ P * , ρ 0 decreases reversibly by an order of magnitude to a very small value of about 0.2 µΩcm. Clearly, pressure does not remove impurities from the sample; the large decrease in ρ 0 must be due to a pressure-induced change in inelastic scattering processes. Theories of electronic transport in quantum-critical systems show that impurity scattering can be strongly enhanced by quantum-critical fluctuations. This sensitivity provides a natural explanation for a decrease in scattering with increasing pressure, if there is a crossover near P * from quantum-critical (P &lt; P * ) to a Fermi-liquid-like state for (P &gt; P * ). Such a crossover is suggested by the pressure variation of n.</p>
		<p>Experimental values of the T n -coefficient of <me_method>resistivity</me_method>, plotted in , also decrease strongly with increasing pressure for P &lt; ∼ P * . For comparison, we show</p>
		<p>(a) Values of ρ0 and n obtained from plots as shown in Fig. 2. (b) Temperature coefficient of <me_method>resistivity</me_method>, A, associated with values of n given in the top panel, and <me_method>specific heat</me_method> coefficient γ measured directly (P &lt; 1.5 GPa) and, for P &gt; <pressure>2 GPa</pressure> , inferred from the T 2 coefficient of ρ(T ). See text for details. (c) Superconducting transition width normalized by <tc>Tc</tc>. ∆Tc and Tc are the half-width of the resistive transition width and resistive midpoint, respectively. Solid lines in all cases are guides to the eye. the variation of the electronic <me_method>specific heat</me_method> divided by temperature (C/T ≡ γ) at 3 K for pressures less than 1.5 GPa and, at higher pressures, we plot values of γ inferred from the empirical relationship A = 1 × 10 −5 γ 2 , where A is the T 2 -coefficient of <me_method>resistivity</me_method>, followed by several heavy-fermion compounds . Though a T 2 coefficient proportional to γ 2 is expected for a Landau Fermi-liquid , it is not obvious a priori why A(P ) approximately tracks the directly measured γ at low pressures, but this seems to be the case. In any event, both A(P ) and γ(P ) exhibit qualitatively different magnitudes and functional dependencies above and below P * . The dramatic differences in γ(P ) at low and high pressures suggest that either the empirical relationship is invalid and underestimates γ in the high-pressure regime by at least two orders of magnitude or there is a very rapid crossover in the density of low-energy excitations in the vicinity of P * . In the Fermi-liquid-like state above P * , we would expect the temperature scale T F L (see</p>
		<p>(a) Temperature-pressure phase diagram for <material>CeCoIn5</material> constructed from data shown in Figs. 2 and 3. (b) Schematic T −P phase diagram. AFM: Néel state; PG: pseudogap state; SC: unconventional superconducting state; FL: Fermi liquid; NFL: non-Fermi-liquid. See text for details. to be proportional to A −0.5 instead of the approximate T F L ∝ √ A found experimentally. We do not understand this discrepancy. Direct measurements of C/T at pressures above P * would be valuable.</p>
		<p>Finally, we note that the resistive transition to the superconducting state is equally sensitive to the crossover at P * . As shown in , the relative transition width ∆T c /T c passes through a pronounced minimum near P * . To some extent this behavior is accentuated by the pressure variation of <tc>T c</tc>, but ∆T c itself is a minimum near P * . It is as if the optimally homogeneous state is singular in the vicinity of P * .</p>
		<p>From the data presented above, we construct a temperature-pressure phase diagram for <material>CeCoIn 5</material> given in . This phase diagram is more like that of the <class>cuprates</class> around optimal doping than the canonical behavior of heavy-fermion systems exemplified, for example, by <material>CeIn 3</material> or <material>CePd 2 Si 2</material> . There is no obvious long-range ordered state in <material>CeCoIn 5</material> at atmospheric or higher pressures. Rather, in view of its relationship to <material>CeRhIn 5</material> , a reasonable speculation is that the antiferromagnetic QCP of <material>CeCoIn 5</material> is at a slightly negative pressure. The <me_method>resistivity</me_method> exponent n and <me_method>specific heat</me_method> (ref. ) are those of a non-Fermi-liquid up to P * where <tc>T c</tc> is a maximum. Beyond P * , <tc>T c</tc> drops rapidly and parameters characterizing electronic transport are qualitatively different, Fermi-liquid-like at temperatures just above <tc>T c</tc> and those of a 3-D quantum-critical antiferromagnetic state at higher temperatures.</p>
		<p>The generic T −P phase diagram in provides a broader perspective of our experimental observations and their relationship to <material>CeRhIn 5</material> . In the spirit of this diagram, the non-Fermi-liquid transport and thermodynamic properties of <material>CeCoIn 5</material> below P * are controlled by an antiferromagnetic QCP at the inaccessible negative pressure denoted by P c in . We have chosen P c to correspond approximately to the critical pressure at which superconductivity appears in <material>CeRhIn 5</material> . Spinlattice relaxation measurements on <material>CeRhIn 5</material> identify [28] a pseudogap whose signature first appears at pressures slightly less than P c and at a temperature of ∼5 K and then decreases toward <tc>T c</tc> with increasing pressure until its signature is lost at P &gt; ∼ P c . If we associate the temperature T pg (P ) in with a resistive signature for a pseudogap and extrapolate T pg (P ) in <material>CeCoIn 5</material> to slightly negative pressures, there is a natural connection between our observations and properties of <material>CeRhIn 5</material> . Neither the 1/T 1 T measurements on <material>CeRhIn 5</material> nor our transport measurements on <material>CeCoIn 5</material> permits definitive statements about the origin or nature of the pseudogap . We note, however, that 4-fold anisotropy of the thermal conductivity in the basal plane of <material>CeCoIn 5</material> persists [12] to 3.2 K ≈ T pg at atmospheric pressure. If this in-plane modulation of the normal-state thermal conductivity is due to the presence of a pseudogap, it implies d-wave symmetry.</p>
		<p>The schematic phase diagram, , reflects the relationship among various phases of <material>CeCoIn 5</material> and <material>CeRhIn 5</material> and is similar to the T -doping phase diagram of the <class>cuprates</class>. This diagram and experimental data from which it is inferred indicate that the physics of heavyfermion systems may be more closely related to that of the <class>cuprates</class> than previously appreciated. Aside from the structural layering in <material>CeCoIn 5</material> and <material>CeRhIn 5</material> and their relatively high <tc>T c</tc>&#x27;s, they are similar in many respects to other Ce-based heavy-fermion materials in which <tc>superconductivity develops</tc> near a QCP. Further study of <material>CeCoIn 5</material> , in parallel with the <class>cuprates</class> and other <class>pressure-induced heavy-fermion superconductors</class>, holds promise for bridging our understanding of the interrelationship between unconventional superconductivity and quantum criticality across these interesting classes of correlated matter.</p>
		<p>We thank R. Movshovich for helpful discussions. VS acknowledges S. M. Stishov for his support during the initial stage of this research. Work at Los Alamos was performed under the auspices of the US Department of Energy.</p>
	</text>
</tei>