<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tei xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc xml:id="_0">
      <titleStmt>
          <title>Anomalous electron-phonon coupling probed on the surface of <rs type="material">ZrB 12</rs> superconductor.</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>National Institute for Materials Science (NIMS), Tsukuba, Japan</publisher>
        <availability>
          <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
            <p>The Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported (CC BY 3.0) Licence applies to this document.</p>
          </licence>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <appInfo>
        <application ident="grobid-superconductors" version="project.version">
          <ref target="https://github.com/lfoppiano/grobid-superconductors">A machine learning software for extracting materials and their properties from scientific literature.</ref>
        </application>
      </appInfo>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <abstract>
          <p><rs type="me_method" xml:id="x2">Magnetization measurements</rs> under hydrostatic pressure up to 10.5 kbar in <rs type="material">zirconium dodeca- boride</rs> <rs type="material" xml:id="x4">ZrB12</rs> superconductor (<rs type="tc">Tc</rs> ≃ <rs corresp="#x2,#x4" type="tcValue" xml:id="x5">6.0 K</rs> at p = <rs corresp="#x5" type="pressure">0</rs>) were carried out. A negative pressure effect on <rs type="tc">Tc</rs> with dTc/dp = −0.0225(3) K/kbar was observed. The electron-phonon coupling constant λ el−ph decreases with increasing pressure with d ln λ el−ph /dp ≃ −0.20%/kbar. The magnetic field penetration depth λ was studied in the Meissner state and, therefore, probes only the surface of the sample. The absolute values of λ and the superconducting energy gap at ambient pressure and zero temperature were found to be λ(0) =140(30) nm and ∆0 =1.251(9) meV, respectively. ∆0 scales linearly with <rs type="tc">Tc</rs> as 2∆0/kBTc = 4.79. The studies of the pressure effect on λ reveal that λ −2 increases with pressure with d ln λ −2 (0)/dp = 0.60(23) %/kbar. This effect can not be explained within the framework of conventional adiabatic electron-phonon pairing, suggesting that close to the surface, an unconventional non-adiabatic character of the electron-phonon coupling takes place.</p>
      </abstract>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text xml:lang="en">
    <body>
      <p>The traditional concept of superconductivity is strictly associated with the electron-phonon interaction. The conventional theory is based on the Migdal-Eliashberg adiabatic approximation that, in fact, leads to the prediction of many peculiar features which are a di- rect evidence of a phonon mediated superconductivity. The adiabatic approximation is valid if the parameter ω 0 /E f is small (ω 0 is the relevant phonon frequency and E f is the Fermi energy). Usually this parameter is regarded as a measure of nonadibaticity. However, crossover from a conventional adiabatic to an unconven- tional nonadiabatic regime does not depend only on the value of the ω 0 /E f ratio. Paci et al. show that even in a case of small "adiabatic" ratio one would ex- pect the nonadiabatic coupling in superconductors hav- ing high value of the electron-phonon coupling constant λ el−ph . Among BCS superconductors the <rs type="material">zirconium do- decaboride</rs> (<rs type="material">ZrB 12</rs> ) is probably a candidate for the ob- servation of such type of anomalous coupling. It stems from the rather small value of the Fermi energy ∼1 eV that, together with the Debye temperature ∼20 meV , leads to a ratio ω 0 /E f ∼0.02. A strong coupling ratio 2∆/k B T c ≃ 4.8 was observed by surface sensitive techniques . This suggests that the electron-phonon coupling constant, which has a bulk value λ el−ph ≃ 0.67 , increases at the surface. From the comparison with strong coupled metallic superconductors one would expect λ surf. el−ph ≃ 1.7 − 1.9. Moreover, it was pointed out by Cappelluti et al. that nonadiabatic character can be further enhanced by low charge carrier density, that is the case for <rs type="material">ZrB 12</rs>.</p>
      <p>One of the key feature of nonadiabatic superconduc- tivity is the observation of unconventional isotope and pressure effects on the magnetic field penetration depth λ. Note, that in adiabatic superconductors (or in the su- perconductors where the nonadiabatic effects are small) the pressure effect (PE) as well as the isotope effect (IE) on λ was found to be almost negligi- ble in comparison with substantial PE and IE on λ observed in highly nonadiabatic high-T c <rs type="class">cuprates</rs>. In this paper we report on PE on <rs type="tc">T c</rs> and λ studies in <rs type="material">ZrB 12</rs> superconductor. The magnetic penetration depth measured in the Meissner state is largely determined by the surface characteristics. The absolute value of λ at zero temperature and zero pressure was found to be λ(0) = 140(30) nm. The <rs type="tc">transition temperature</rs> <rs type="tc">T c</rs> and the electron-phonon coupling constant decrease with pressure with the pressure effect coefficients dT c /dp = −0.0225(3) K/kbar and d ln λ el−ph /dp ≃ −0.2%/kbar, respectively. In contrast to <rs type="tc">T c</rs> , λ −2 (0) was found to in- crease with dλ −2 (0)/dp = 0.29(11) µm −2 /kbar. Only a small part of this effect can be explained by a pressure induced renormalization of the electron-phonon interac- tion and the band structure changes. The major part is probably a consequence of nonadibatic coupling of the charge carriers to the crystal lattice appearing in <rs type="material">ZrB 12</rs> close to the surface.</p>
      <p>Details on the sample preparation for <rs type="material">ZrB 12</rs> can be found elsewhere . The single crystal has been grounded in mortar and then sieved via 10 µm sieve in order to obtain small grains needed for determination of λ from <rs type="me_method">magnetization</rs> measurements. The grain size dis-tribution was determined by analyzing scanning electron microscope (SEM) photographs. The hydrostatic pres- sure was generated in a copper-beryllium piston cylin- der clamp especially designed for <rs type="me_method">magnetization</rs> measure- ments under pressure . The sample was mixed with Fluorient FC77 (pressure transmitting medium) with a sample-to-liquid volume ratio of approximately 1/6. The pressure dependence of <rs type="tc">T c</rs> was taken from a separate set of <rs type="me_method">magnetization</rs> experiments where a small piece of <rs type="material" xml:id="x5-131">in- dium</rs> [<rs type="tc">T c</rs> (p = <rs type="pressure">0</rs>) = <rs corresp="#x5-131" type="tcValue">3.4 K</rs>] with known <rs type="tc">T c</rs> (p) dependence was added to the sample and both <rs type="tc">T c</rs> 's of <rs type="material">indium</rs> and <rs type="material">ZrB 12</rs> were recorded. The field-cooled (FC) <rs type="me_method">magnetiza- tion</rs> measurements were performed with a SQUID mag- netometer in a field of 0.5 mT at temperatures between 1.75 K and 10 K. The absence of weak links between grains was confirmed by the linear magnetic field depen- dence of the FC magnetization, measured at 0.25 mT, 0.5 mT, and 1.0 mT for the highest and the lowest pres- sures at T = 1.75 K. shows the pressure dependence of the <rs type="tc">tran- sition temperature</rs> <rs type="tc">T c</rs> of <rs type="material">ZrB 12</rs> obtained from <rs type="me_method">magneti- zation</rs> measurements.</p>
      <p><rs type="tc">T c</rs> was taken from the linearly extrapolated M (T ) curves in the vicinity of <rs type="tc">T c</rs> with M = 0 line (see inset in Fig. 1). The linear fit yields Pressure dependence of the <rs type="tc">transition temperature</rs> <rs type="tc">Tc</rs> for <rs type="material">ZrB12</rs>. The errors are smaller than the size of the symbols. The inset shows M (T ) curves in the vicinity of <rs type="tc">Tc</rs> for (from the left to the right) 10.36, 4.89, and 0.0 kbar. dT c /dp = −0.0225(3) K/kbar. Note that this value is in good agreement with dT c /dp ≃ −0.024 K/kbar obtained indirectly by Lortz et al. from thermal expansion mea- surements.</p>
      <p>The logarithmic volume derivative of <rs type="tc">T c</rs> in case of strong coupled BCS superconductor can be described by the following equation : where is a function of the electron-phonon cou- pling constant λ el−ph and the Coulomb pseudopotential µ * , B denotes the bulk modulus, γ = −d ln ω /d ln V is the Grüneisen parameter, ω is an average phonon frequency, η ≡ N (E f ) I 2 is the Hopfeld parameter . N (E f ) is the density of states at the Fermi level, and I 2 is the average squared electronic matrix el- ement. The Hopfeld parameter η generally increases under pressure with d ln η/d ln V ≈ −1 for s-, and p- metal superconductors and −3 to −4 for transition- metal (d-electron) superconductors . Assuming that d ln η/d ln V ≃ −1, B = 2490 kbar in analogy with <rs type="material">UB 12</rs> , µ * = 0.1 (that is the typical value for conventional phonon-mediated superconductors (see e.g. Ref. ), and taking λ el−ph ≃ 0.67 , for the Grüniesen parameter we get the value γ ≃ 2.83. This value is in reasonable agree- ment with γ ≃ 3.3 obtained at a temperature slightly above <rs type="tc">T c</rs> by Lortz et al. based on thermal expansion measurements. PE on the electron-phonon coupling constant λ el−ph can be determined by using the well-known McMillan equation which leads to Substitution of γ = 2.83 and d ln η/d ln V = −1 gives d ln λ el−ph /dp = −0.19%/kbar. A slightly larger value d ln λ el−ph /dp = −0.22%/kbar is obtained with γ = 3.3 from the Ref. . As a next step we studied the pressure effect on the magnetic field penetration depth λ. The temperature dependence of λ was calculated from the measured FC <rs type="me_method">magnetization</rs> by using the Shoenberg formula , mod- ified for the known grain size distribution N (R) : where χ = M/HV is the volume susceptibility, V is the volume of the sample, R is the grain radius and g(R) is the analytical function describing the N (R)R 3 depen- dence (see inset in . The resulting temperature de- pendence λ −2 (T ) at ambient pressure is shown in .</p>
      <p>The temperature dependence of λ −2 calculated from the measured <rs type="me_method">χ(T )</rs> by using Eq. (4). Lines represent fits with the BCS model (dashed line), and with a power law (solid line). See text for an explanation. The inset shows the volume fraction distribution N (R)R 3 of the <rs type="material">ZrB12</rs> powder determined from SEM photographs. The errors are statistical. The solid line represent the analytical g(R) function used in Eq. (4). The reconstructed data were fitted with the empirical power-law λ −2 (T )/λ −2 (0) = 1 − (T /T c ) n . The fit yields λ −2 (0) = 48.4(2) µm −2 , <rs type="tc">T c</rs> = <rs type="tcValue">6.078(5) K</rs>, and n = 3.65(4). Note, that the value of the power exponent n is close to "4" which corresponds to a strong-coupled BCS superconductor .</p>
      <p>In order to obtain the value of the superconducting gap ∆, the data have also been analyzed by means of the BCS model. For clean superconductor the temperature dependence of λ −2 can be described in the following way : where F = (1 + exp(E/k B T ) −1 is the Fermi function, ∆(T ) = ∆ 0 •∆(T /T c ) represents the temperature de- pendence of the energy gap, and ∆ 0 is the zero tem- perature value of the superconducting gap.∆(T /T c ) is the normalized gap taken from Ref. . The best fit to the data using Eq. gives <rs type="tc">T c</rs> = <rs corresp="#x39" type="tcValue">6.09(2) K</rs>, λ −2 (0) = 47.4(2) nm, and ∆ 0 = 1.251(9) meV. The ra- tio 2∆ 0 /k B T c = 4.77(4) is found, suggesting that <rs type="material">ZrB 12</rs> is a strong coupled BCS superconductor. Note, that a rather close value 2∆ 0 /k B T c ≃ 4.8 has been obtained in point-contact spectroscopy and tunnelling ex- periments. From the other hand a smaller value ≃3.7 has been reported by Lortz et al. using the heat- capacitance technique, thus suggesting a weak coupling strength. This difference has been already pointed out by Tsindlekht et al. . It was explained by enhanced surface characteristics of the <rs type="material" xml:id="x39">ZrB 12</rs> leading to rather dif- ferent superconducting properties of bulk and surface . Our measurements were performed in the Meissner state, with the field penetrating on a dis- tance λ from the surface and, therefore, give a value of the superconducting gap consistent with those one reported in the surface sensitive experiments . To estimate the uncertainty in the absolute value of λ(0) we used a procedure similar to that one described in Refs. . The temperature dependence of λ(T ) was calculated for N (R) + N (R) and N (R) − N (R) distributions. The fit of the resulting λ(T ) curves with the power law as well as with the BCS model gives λ(0) in the range from 110 to 170 nm. shows the pressure dependence of λ −2 (0) obtained by fitting the reconstructed λ(T ) data at dif- ferent pressures with the BCS model [Eq. ]. In these experiments we studied relative effects measured on the same sample in the same pressure cell. The main system- atic error of these measurements comes from misalign- ments of the experimental setup occurring when the cell is removed from the SQUID magnetometer, to change the pressure, and put back again. This procedure was checked with a set of measurements at constant pressure. The systematic scattering of the <rs type="me_method">magnetization</rs> data is about 0.3%, giving a relative error in λ −2 (T ) of about 3%. The reducing of the grain size with pressure was taken into account in λ(T ) calculation [Eq. (4)], by using the bulk modulus reported above. The linear fit yields λ −2 (0) = 48.4(7)+ 0.29p implying that λ −2 increases under pressure with d ln λ −2 (0)/dp = 0.60(23)%/kbar [see ].</p>
      <p>To analyze the observed effect we used a procedure similar to that one described by Di Castro et al. . There, it was suggested that λ −2 increases under pressure because of two reasons: (i) band structure effects and (ii) renormalization of the electron-phonon coupling . Under the assumption of ellipsoidal or cylindrical Fermi surface the first one can be obtained as d ln λ −2 (0) dp Here we used the fact that the pressure dependence of the electronic matrix element I 2 entering the Hopfeld parameter η can usually be neglected . Hence, by set- ting d ln η/d ln V ≃ −1, and B = 2490 kbar (see above) we obtain d ln λ −2 (0)/dp = 0.05%/kbar. The electron-phonon renormalized penetration depth</p>
      <p>Pressure dependences of λ −2 (0) (a) and 2∆0/kB Tc (b). The solid lines are fits with parameters shown in figures. reduces to λ * −2 (0) = λ −2 (0)/(1 + λ el−ph ) , where λ(0) is the bare quantity we have considered before.</p>
      <p>By substituting λ el−ph ≃ 0.67 and d ln λ el−ph /dp ≃ −0.2%/kbar obtained above we get d ln λ * −2 (0)/dp ≃ 0.08%/kbar . Thus the total pressure shift of λ −2 (0) expected assuming conventional (adiabatic) coupling of the charge carriers to the lattice in <rs type="material">ZrB 12</rs> is of the order of 0.13%/kbar. This value is more than three times smaller than the experimentally observed one 0.60(22)%/kbar. This implies that in addition to band structure ef- fects and renormalization of the electron-phonon cou- pling there are other effects responsible for the increas- ing of λ −2 (0) under pressure. Bearing in mind that λ measurements have been performed in a Meissner state, the observed dependence of λ on p can be explained as- suming that in <rs type="material">ZrB 12</rs> close to the surface the coupling of the charge carriers to the lattice has a nonadiabatic character. Note that similar effect have been observed in <rs type="material">YBa 2 Cu 4 O 8</rs> that appears to be a highly nonadiabtic superconductor .</p>
      <p>The results on the zero temperature superconducting gap ∆ 0 are summarized in , where the ratio 2∆ 0 /k B T c is plotted as a function of the pressure p. ∆ 0 and <rs type="tc">T c</rs> were obtained from the fit of λ −2 (T, p) data by us- ing Eq. (5). The solid line represents a fit by the relation 2∆ 0 /k B T c = const to the data. Bearing in mind that <rs type="tc">T c</rs> scales linearly with pressure (see ) the constant ratio can be understood in the frame of the BCS theory, which predicts 2∆ 0 /k B T c = 3.52. In the present study this ratio was found to be pressure independent within experimental errors, with mean value 4.79(1).</p>
      <p>In conclusion, we performed <rs type="me_method">magnetization</rs> measure- ments in <rs type="material">ZrB 12</rs> under hydrostatic pressure. A negative pressure effect on <rs type="tc">T c</rs> with dT c /dp = −0.0225(3) K/kbar is observed. The electron-phonon coupling constant λ el−ph decreases with pressure with d ln λ el−ph /dp ≃ −0.20%/kbar. The magnetic field penetration depth λ measured in the Meissner state is largely determined by the surface characteristics. λ was found to in- crease with pressure, with the pressure effect coefficient d ln λ −2 (0)/dp = 0.60(23)%/kbar. This coefficient is much larger than that one estimated theoretically within the adiabatic approximation. This can be explained by considering that in <rs type="material">ZrB 12</rs>, close to the surface, the cou- pling of the charge carriers to the lattice has a nonadia- batic character. The ratio 2∆ 0 /k B T c = 4.79(1) is found to be pressure independent and close to the strong cou- pling BCS value 4.8(1) reported in Refs. . The value of λ extrapolated to zero temperature and at p = 0 was estimated to be 140(30) nm.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</tei>
