<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tei xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc xml:id="_0">
      <titleStmt>
          <title>Antiferromagnetic ordering in a 90 K <rs type="class">copper oxide</rs> superconductor.</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>National Institute for Materials Science (NIMS), Tsukuba, Japan</publisher>
        <availability>
          <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
            <p>The Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported (CC BY 3.0) Licence applies to this document.</p>
          </licence>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <appInfo>
        <application ident="grobid-superconductors" version="project.version">
          <ref target="https://github.com/lfoppiano/grobid-superconductors">A machine learning software for extracting materials and their properties from scientific literature.</ref>
        </application>
      </appInfo>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <abstract>
          <p>Using elastic neutron scattering, we evidence a commensurate antiferromagnetic Cu(2) order (AF) in the superconducting (SC) high-Tc <rs type="class">cuprate</rs> <rs type="material" xml:id="x2">YBa2(Cu1−yCoy)3O 7+δ (y=0.013</rs>, <rs type="tc">Tc</rs>=<rs corresp="#x2" type="tcValue">93 K</rs>). However, the spin excitation spectrum is still dominated by a magnetic resonance peak at 41 meV as in the Co-free system, but with a reduced spectral weight. The substitution of Co thus leads to a state where AF and SC cohabit. These results show that the hole-doped CuO2 plane is close to an AF instability even when Tc remains optimum.</p>
      </abstract>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text xml:lang="en">
    <body>
      <p>The interplay between magnetic order and <rs type="tc">supercon- ductivity</rs> is an interesting and profound phenomenon ubiquitous in strongly correlated systems, such as high-T c <rs type="class">cuprates</rs>, low-T c <rs type="class">ruthenates</rs> and <rs type="class">heavy fermions</rs> systems. There have been a number of reports of the coexistence of magnetic order and exotic super- conductivity: for example, in Ce and U-based <rs type="class">heavy fermion</rs> systems , in <rs type="material">superoxygenated La 2 CuO 4+δ</rs> , in <rs type="material">La 1.6−x Nd 0.4 Sr x CuO 4</rs> and more recently in the well <rs type="material">underdoped regime of YBa 2 Cu 3 O 6+x (x=0.5-0.6)</rs> . In the last case , the observation that the magnetic in- tensity decreases at large momentum more rapidly than does the Cu-spin form factor, has been considered to support the suggestion of orbital moments of a d-wave density-wave (DDW) order parameter (that could be the hidden order responsible for the "pseudo-gap phase" of underdoped <rs type="class">cuprates</rs>) . However, in the <rs type="class">cuprates</rs>, the real coexistence of magnetic order and superconductiv- ity or a microscopic phase segregation remains a matter of discussion. Especially, the role played by disorder is still an open question . In this letter, we evidence the appearance of antiferromagnetic order in the CuO 2 planes of a <rs type="material" xml:id="x9">fully oxydised superconducting YBa 2 Cu 3 O 7</rs> based system with <rs type="tc">T c</rs> =<rs corresp="#x9" type="tcValue">93 K</rs>, when a disorder is intro- duced through the substitution of cobalt atoms at the copper site of the chains.</p>
      <p>The YBa 2 Cu 3 O 6+x perovskite structure contains two copper sites: Cu(1) belonging to the Cu-O chains (along the b-axis), and Cu(2) belonging to the CuO 2 planes. Co 3+ ions substitute only at the Cu(1) sites . Due to its higher oxidation state compared to that of Cu(1), the Co cation pulls in extra oxygen to increase its oxygen- coordination. Each added Co atom, with an average coordination number of 5, pulls in 0.5 oxygen atoms . Additionally, the Co substitution induces a trans- verse distortion of its Cu(1) site . Co atoms tend to form either small clusters like dimers or even short chains along the (110) direction . As a result, these chains pin down the twin boundaries of the or- thorhombic structure (micro-twinning) that triggers an orthorhombic-tetragonal transition for y ≥ 0.025 . NMR and transport measurements show the cobalt substitution reduces the hole doping. However, for the low Co substitution level (<rs type="material">y ≃ 0.013</rs>) examined here, despite the decrease in the Hall effect derived car- rier density and in the <rs type="me_method">specific heat</rs> derived conden- sate density , the doping is still high enough for <rs type="tc">T c</rs> to remain at its optimum value. In addition, Nuclear Quadrupole Resonance (NQR) measurements have evidenced the appearance of magnetic moments on the Cu of the Cu(1) sites and more surprisingly on those of the Cu(2) sites as well. Mössbauer probe measurements have also evidenced the moments on the Cu(2) sites.</p>
      <p>We present a neutron scattering study of the magnetic properties of a large <rs type="material">single crystal (1.4 cm 3 ) of fully oxy- genated YBa 2 (Cu 1−y Co y ) 3 O 7+δ</rs> . The sample was pre- pared by the top-seed melt texturing method. A mi- croprobe analysis confirmed the Co content was that of the starting mixture, <rs type="material" xml:id="x16">y=0.013</rs>, and showed the Co was uniformly distributed on the µm scale. Neutron depolar- ization measurements c) provided <rs type="tc">T c</rs> = <rs corresp="#x16" type="tcValue">93 K</rs>.</p>
      <p>The neutron scattering experiments were performed on the triple axis spectrometers 1T1 and 4F2 at the Labora- toire Léon Brillouin, Saclay (France). For elastic neutron scattering measurements (ENS) on 4F2, double PG(002) monochromators and analyzer were used and a beryllium filter was inserted into the scattered beam in order to re- move higher order contamination. The data were taken with a fixed final wavevector of 1.55Å −1 . For the in- elastic neutron scattering measurements (INS) on 1T1, a focusing Cu(110) monochromator and a PG(002) an- alyzer were used and a pyrolytic graphite filter was in- serted into the scattered beam. The data were taken with a fixed final wavevector of 4.1Å −1 . Measurements were carried out with the crystal in two different orientations where wave vector transfers of the form Q=(H, H, L) and (3H, H, L), respectively, were accessible. Throughout this article, the wave vector Q is indexed in units of the re- ciprocal tetragonal lattice vectors 2π/a=2π/b=1.63Å −1 and 2π/c=0.53Å −1 . In this notation the (π/a, π/a) wave</p>
      <p>Elastic neutron intensity along a) the (110) di- rection and b) the (001) direction around Q=(0.5,0.5,1). c) L-dependence of magnetic intensity at different AF peaks, Q=(0.5,0.5,L). The full line represents the magnetic inten- sity expected from in-plane Cu(2) spins with isotropic Cu 2+ form factor and including the resolution correction. d) Tem- perature dependences of the neutron scattering intensity at Q=(0.5,0.5,1). The full squares represent the background from scans as shown in a) and b). Inset of d) shows the ap- pearance of magnetic intensity at Q=(0.5,0.5,1.5) below Tm ≃ 12 K where the peak at Q=(0.5,0.5,1) displays a re-entrant behavior.</p>
      <p>vector parallel to the CuO 2 planes corresponds to points of the form (h/2,k/2) with h and k odd integers.</p>
      <p>We first describe the observation of the commensurate magnetic order. shows the elastic neutron inten- sity at the antiferromagnetic wavevector Q=(0.5,0.5,1) along both the (110) and (001) directions. The peak, absent at 338 K and present at 250 K and 40 K, evi- dences the magnetic order. Different antiferromagnetic peaks, Q=(0.5,0.5,L) with L integer, are reported in .c where magnetic intensity is sizeable at L=1,2,3. The observed pattern (.c) and the absence of any mag- netic peak at Q=(0.5,0.5,0) implies that the magnetic response is fully dominated by magnetic moments at the Cu(2) sites. Assuming all of the Cu(2) carry the same ordered moment, we obtain a low temperature (T=40 K) mean moment of ∼ 0.10 ± 0.05µ B . Gaussian fits of at different temperatures shows that the AF order is resolution limited, meaning that the correlation lengths are typically ξ &gt; 200Å. A detailed q-dependence of the magnetic peak, see for instance the double peak struc- ture of the scan along c * of .b, shows a mosaic distribution of the magnetic peak which does not exactly reproduce that of the nuclear peaks. This means that the volume of AF region does not exactly match the volume of the single crystal.</p>
      <p>The temperature dependence of the neutron scatter- ing intensity measured at the antiferromagnetic wavevec- tor Q=(0.5,0.5,1) (shows the system orders at T N ∼ 330 K. As the temperature is lowered, the AF Bragg intensity initially increases continuously and no anomaly is observed on passing through <rs type="tc">T c</rs> . The peak intensity displays a marked downturn at T m ≃ 12 K, and almost half of its intensity is left as T→ 0. Below T m , ad- ditional neutron intensity occurs at L=1.5 indicating the system undergoes an AFI-AFII transition, characterized by the doubling of the AF unit cell along the c axis. This transition is also observed in <rs type="material">YBa 2 Cu 3 O 6</rs> when substi- tuted at the Cu(1) site and AFII ordering is ob- served in <rs type="material">non-superconducting YBa 2 (Cu 1−y Co y ) 3 O 7+δ</rs> with high Co substitution levels . The re-ordering ob- served in the present case may be linked to the influence of magnetic freezing which is known to exist in in simi- lar samples, For example, in <rs type="material">YBa 2 (Cu 0.94 Co 0.06 ) 3 O 7+δ</rs>, time of flight neutron scattering measurements have evidenced the progressive freezing of the Co moments as the temperature is lowered in agreement with local probe measurements .</p>
      <p>Without producing any reduction in the <rs type="tc">superconduct- ing transition temperature</rs>, the substitution of magnetic Co 3+ at the chain sites thus introduces a very specific perturbation which induces a commensurate AF 3D or- der, below T N ∼ 330 K, at the copper sites of the CuO 2 planes. A key question is how does the superconductivity and the antiferromagnetic order cohabit ?</p>
      <p>To address this issue, we first consider the possibility of complete phase segregation, such that only a small frac- tion of Cu(2) atoms, for example those adjacent to a Co atom, carries the full magnetic moment of the undoped <rs type="class">cuprates</rs> (0.6 µ B ). The concentration of Cu(2) atoms (in the planes) needed to account for the observed scattering intensity would then be ∼ 3 % which is roughly compara- ble to the Co substitution level (in the chains). There are a number of arguments against this hypothesis. As the magnetic correlation length exceeds 200Å, then the Co would be essentially concentrated within these clusters. Such Co clusters would yield an observable magnetic diffraction pattern. The local Co concentration would also be quite high and we would expect to observe the be- havior seen in samples having high Co levels. For exam- ple, insulating samples of <rs type="material">YBa 2 (Cu 1−y (Co, Fe) y ) 3 O 7+δ</rs> show the AFII structure up to T N ∼ 400 K, whereas it is the AFI structure that is observed here at T N . Neither of these features is observed. Further ar-</p>
      <p>Difference of constant energy scans performed at 39 meV measured at low temperature, and just above Tc: a) around Q=(0.5,0.5,-5.4) along the (110) direction: b)around Q=(1.5,0.5,-1.7) along the (310) direction. Solid lines are fit by Gaussian lineshape. guments against complete phase separation is provided by Cu-NQR or Y-NMR local probe measure- ments in <rs type="material">YBa 2 (Cu 1−y Co y ) 3 O 7+δ</rs> which evidence features that are different from those of the undoped insulating AF state. We recall also that local probe Cu NQR and Mössbauer measurements on samples having the same low Co substitution level as the sample studied here have shown that over 50 % of the Cu(2) carry magnetic moments. Thus, it does not seem possible that the AF order could be linked to the existence of locally undoped regions. Consequently, the two phenomena (AF and SC) appear to be in contact at a microscopic level.</p>
      <p>As the Co atoms aggregate into dimers or small clus- ters forming lines along the (110) direction , we spec- ulate that these lines of magnetic Co atoms are the per- turbing elements which induce the AF order into the CuO 2 planes. However, we recall the Cu(2) moments are not confined to the immediate vicinity of these lines for the magnetic correlation lengths greatly exceed the lateral dimensions of a twin boundary.</p>
      <p>Finally, we believe this new AF order is analogous to that recently reported in <rs type="material">underdoped YBa 2 Cu 3 O 6+x (x ∼ 0.5 -0.6)</rs> with however one striking difference: the additional enhancement of the AF intensity observed below <rs type="tc">T c</rs> is not seen in the present case. At large Q, the intensity decreases much more rapidly than expected for the Cu-spin form factor (see . This result is sim- ilar to that observed in well <rs type="material">underdoped YBa 2 Cu 3 O 6.6</rs> where it was interpreted as evidencing DDW order . Our finding of a similar unusual structure factor in a Co-substituted sample which is near optimal doping and where a pseudo-gap behavior is absent, questions this conclusion. The precise reason for the observed struc- ture factor remains unclear at present. We next present the inelastic magnetic fluctuations around the AF wavevector. In <rs type="material">cobalt-free optimally doped YBa 2 Cu 3 O 7−δ</rs>, the AF correlations are purely dy-</p>
      <p>T=95 K. The scan above Tc looks very similar to that in the Co-free sample with the phonon peak at 42.5 meV . b) Difference between energy scans performed at 9.2 K (or 70 K) and at 95 K. c) determination of <rs type="tc">Tc</rs> = <rs type="tcValue">93 K</rs> by the neutron depolarisation technique. d) temperature dependence of the AF response at 35 meV and 42 meV.</p>
      <p>namic, and the spin excitation spectrum in the supercon- ducting state is characterized by a sharp antiferromag- netic excitation peaked at 41 meV, the so-called "mag- netic resonance peak" . In our cobalt substituted sample, we looked for this magnetic excitation specific of d-wave superconductivity and we performed constant energy scans at 39 meV around Q=(0.5,0.5,-5.4) along the (110) direction as well as around (1.5,0.5,-1.7) along the (310) direction . At low temperature, a peak shows up in both scans centered at the AF wave vector. The ratio of the intensity of both scans evolves as a func- tion of Q as expected for the Cu 2+ anisotropic magnetic form factor . In both scans, the peak diminishes dras- tically at <rs type="tc">T c</rs> . Above <rs type="tc">T c</rs> , weaker intensity, peaked at AF wavevector, remains in both scans, in agreement with the <rs type="material">Co-free compound YBa 2 Cu 3 O 6.97</rs> . After subtraction of the scan just above <rs type="tc">T c</rs> from that at low temperature, the remaining intensity was fitted to a Gaussian profile centered at the AF wave vector. For both types of con- stant energy scans reported in , the AF response at 39 meV in the superconducting state displays a mo- mentum width (FWHM) of 0.28 ± 0.06Å −1 . This mo- mentum distribution is similar to that of the magnetic resonance peak in the <rs type="material">Co-free system</rs> . shows energy scans performed at Q=(0.5,0.5,-5.4) at low temperature and just above <rs type="tc">T c</rs> . The enhance-ment of the AF response around 41 meV (the magnetic resonance peak) is visible in the raw data and it is fur- ther confirmed by the differences shown on .b. The magnetic resonance peak is not sharp in energy and can be fitted by the usual "ansatz" of a single Gaussian line- shape: this yields an intrinsic energy width of ∼ 9 ± 1 meV (FWHM). This analysis in terms of a single broad signal centered at E r is supported by the temperature de- pendences performed at the AF wave vector at 42 meV and 35 meV (6 meV below E r ) which both show a simi- lar decrease of the AF response up to <rs type="tc">T c</rs> . As a function of temperature, the magnetic resonance peak disappears at <rs type="tc">T c</rs> without any significant shift of its char- acteristic energy . Furthermore, its energy and momentum integrated intensity, calibrated in absolute unit against the phonon at 42.5 meV, is ∼ 0.025 µ 2 B , i.e it is about twice weaker than that reported in the <rs type="material">Co-free compound</rs> .</p>
      <p>The spin dynamics observed following Co substitution (at the Cu(1) site) show some features which are common to those observed with Ni and Zn substitutions (at the Cu(2) site), where a broadened magnetic resonance peak was also seen . However, the Ni and Zn substitutions have more drastic effects on the dynamical AF correla- tions: Zn already induces strong AF fluctuations in the normal state although it reduces the enhancement of the spin <rs type="me_method">susceptibility</rs> in the SC state, whereas Ni renormal- izes the resonance energy.</p>
      <p>Following the observed 50% reduction in the weight of the resonance peak, it is possible that distinct su- perconducting regions occupy about half of the sample volume leaving the remainder for the distinct magneti- cally ordered regions. This fully agrees with NQR re- sults on sample with similar Co content which show that about half the Cu(2) carry magnetic moments . Such a phase segregation scenario has some analogies with the three phase model developed to explain the Cu-NQR data . However, the magnetic correlation lengths found here (ξ &gt; 200Å) are much bigger than the dimensions of the nucleated regions where the Cu(2) become magnetic as considered in ref. . In addition, Kohno et al. have proposed a phenomenological description of AF-SC coexistent states due to disorder in strongly correlated systems. In their model, based on Ginsburg-Landau the- ory, a key assumption is that the SC state is in competi- tion with the AF phase with a first order phase bound- ary, which enables the AF state to nucleate where SC is suppressed. For a finite concentration of impurities, the first order AF-SC boundary of the clean case is re- placed by a finite region where the SC and AF moments coexist microscopically with spatially varying order pa- rameters. It has also been proposed that an AF state can locally appear around surfaces or impurities and can co-exist with d-wave superconductivity and in particular, the local formation of an AF order parameter can easily occur near a (110) surface. The AF order in the present case could have its origin in the magnetic polarisation produced by the Co 3+ or in the structural effects related to the micro-twinning along the (110) directions or more probably, to a combination of both these effects.</p>
      <p>As a conclusion, we observe a Cu(2) site commensu- rate long range AF order in the superconducting high-T c <rs type="class">cuprate</rs> <rs type="material" xml:id="x40">YBa 2 (Cu 1−y Co y ) 3 O 7+δ (y=0.013</rs>, <rs type="tc">T c</rs> =<rs corresp="#x40" type="tcValue">93 K</rs>). The observed structure factors differ slightly from that for the Cu(2) spins in the undoped state of the cuprates. This difference, observed in a sample where the doping level is high enough to support an optimum <rs type="tc">T c</rs> value, questions the conclusion that a similar observation in well <rs type="material">underdoped YBa 2 Cu 3 O 6.6</rs> is evidence for the predicted DDW order in the pseudo-gap phase. The cohabitation of AF and SC can be described as a formation of an AF phase within a d-wave superconductor. Whatever the precise mechanism giving rise to the AF ordering, our results reveal that hole-doped CuO 2 plane is close to an AF instability even when <rs type="tc">T c</rs> remains optimum.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</tei>
